<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://digitator.in/news</link>
    <atom:link href="http://digitator.in/news/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description></description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 08:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 08:20:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>

    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping murders</title>
      <link>http://digitator.in/news/funeral/2015/10/29/mapping-murders/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://digitator.in/news/funeral/2015/10/29/mapping-murders</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recent release of the book about the Aarushi murders goes into great details about the case. Her death, the death of the help in the house and the subsequent case and trials. The book contains maps of the Aarushi’s home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/news/assets/aarushi.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While looking at this kind of detailed map of one murder, I wonder if it will be useful mapping other murders. Murders that do not get as much attention as this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drawing maps and locating these murders geographically and categorizing them as urban/rural, socio-economic caste status will help show a pattern. I think we already know the pattern that will emerge. The murders that constantly draw our attention and are covered in the news are ones where the victims are urban middle and upper-middle class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murders committed against dalits living in rural India do not warrant more than a small column in the news. Barely a passing scrolling mention on TV. But certainly no detailed analysis about how petrol was bought, where was the petrol purchased from, how was it poured through windows and a family set on fire. How the parents tried to rescue their children and burned themselves in the process while they watched their children burn to death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do we relish in the gristly details of murders of people like Aarushi, Sheena Bora and others? And where is the same appetite for information when two children are burned to death? Their names are not even known (Vaibhav and Divya). They are just two anonymous dalit children who died. One more to the toll of anonymous people who die everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is socio-economics and caste the driving factor in making these murders anonymous? Is it because we can relate to people like Aarushi and her family. The kind of urban middle-class hard working family who are apsiring to own apartments, TVs , cars and phones and want to put their children through good schools. These are the kinds of people that we can relate to. The poor who live in rural and even in urban India have very different lives. Lives that are far removed from our own existence living within a rapidly modernizing India. In apartment complexes that appear to have been produced from some kind of global design process, to make our globalized work force feel at home regardless of where they live. India, China, somewhere in the South-East. It doesn’t matter. The deaths of anyone of us or those aspiring to be like us is a matter of curiosity. Perhaps the coverage makes for better reality TV than our reality TV. Because we know how distorted these artists imaginations are… They can never seem to capture reality quite the way it is. The way we see it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The deaths of a few children in a village somewhere, oh its sad no doubt. But like VK Singh said. Each time someone throws stones at a dog, or kills some poor children neither the government nor we the people striving to serve the government and the corporates and lodging our protests when they do us wrong should be too bothered.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Whats the beef?</title>
      <link>http://digitator.in/news/food/2015/10/26/Whats-the-beef/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://digitator.in/news/food/2015/10/26/Whats-the-beef</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The forcible shutting of butcher shops and banning of beef through threat of violence means simply eating beef has become an assertion of our individual liberty or freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time there is a global movement calling for the ban of the meat industry citing it as one of the big contributors to global warming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We intend to look closer into this issue and try and understand the specifics of how an animal’s flatulence is measured and how much pollution the Indian meat industry might be contributing and how that compares to the emissions of other global industries like war, transport and consumer goods?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If climate change is a reality and the likelihood of catastrophic local changes in weather patterns, crop production and other food sources are increased, then rather than banning meat would it make more sense to look to diversify food sources and try and increase the kinds of foods that people especially the marginalized have access to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the next few months Joice and I hope to dive into and understand meat both locally and globally. &lt;a href=&quot;/meat/&quot;&gt;Meat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    

  </channel> 
</rss>
